<resources>
    <string name="app_name">SimpleStart</string>
    <string name="name_hint">Character Name</string>
    <string name="dragonborn">Dragonborn</string>
    <string name="drow">Dark Elf (Drow)</string>
    <string name="forestgnome">Forest Gnome</string>
    <string name="helf">Half Elf</string>
    <string name="highelf">High Elf</string>
    <string name="hilldwarf">Hill Dwarf</string>
    <string name="horc">Half Orc</string>
    <string name="human">Human</string>
    <string name="lighthalfling">Lightfoot Halfling</string>
    <string name="mountaindwarf">Mountain Dwarf</string>
    <string name="rockgnome">Rock Gnome</string>
    <string name="stouthalfling">Stout Halfling</string>
    <string name="tiefling">Tiefling</string>
    <string name="woodelf">Wood Elf</string>
    <string name="ability0">Str + 2, Cha + 1</string>
    <string name="ability1">Dex + 2, Cha + 1</string>
    <string name="ability2">Dex + 2, Int + 1</string>
    <string name="ability3">Dex + 2, Wis + 1</string>
    <string name="ability4">Cha + 2</string>
    <string name="ability5">All + 1</string>
    <string name="ability6">Int + 2, Dex + 1</string>
    <string name="ability7">Int + 2, Con + 1</string>
    <string name="ability8">Con + 2, Wis + 1</string>
    <string name="ability9">Con + 2, Str + 2</string>
    <string name="ability10">Str + 2, Con + 1</string>
    <string name="ability11">Dex + 2, Cha + 1</string>
    <string name="ability12">Dex + 2, Con + 1</string>
    <string name="ability13">Cha + 2, Int + 1</string>
    <string name="sizeM">Size: Medium</string>
    <string name="sizeS">Size: Small</string>
    <string name="spd25">Speed: 25ft</string>
    <string name="spd30">Speed: 30ft</string>
    <string name="spd35">Speed: 35ft</string>
    <string name="traits0"></string>
    <string name="traits1"></string>
    <string name="traits2"></string>
    <string name="traits3"></string>
    <string name="traits4"></string>
    <string name="traits5"></string>
    <string name="traits6"></string>
    <string name="traits7"></string>
    <string name="traits8"></string>
    <string name="traits9"></string>
    <string name="traits10"></string>
    <string name="traits11"></string>
    <string name="traits12"></string>
    <string name="traits13"></string>
    <!--These extra strings are only for non-unique race traits (this include traits that are
    simply shared between subraces). Unique race traits will most likely go in the race's own
    traits string.-->
    <string name="darkvision"><b>Darkvision.</b> You can see in dim light within 60 ft as if it were
        bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness,
        only shades of gray.</string>
    <string name="dwarvenResilience"><b>Dwarven Resilience.</b> You have advantage on saving throws
        against poision, and you have resistance against poison damage.</string>
    <string name="dwarvenCombatTraining"><b>Dwarven Combat Training.</b> You have proficiency with
        the battleaxe, handaxe, throwing hammer, and warhammer.</string>
    <string name="dwarvenToolProficiency"><b>Tool Proficiency.</b> You gain proficiency with the
        artisan's tools of your choic: smith's tools, brewer's supplies, or mason's tools.</string>
    <string name="stonecunning"><b>Stonecunning.</b> Whenever you make an Intelligence (History)
        check related to the origin of stonework, you are considered proficient in History and add
        double your proficiency bonus, instead of your normal proficiency bonus.</string>
    <string name="dwarvenToughness"><b>Dwarven Toughness.</b> Your hit point maximum increases by 1,
        and it increases by an additional 1 every time you gain a level.</string>
    <string name="dwarvenArmorTraining"><b>Dwarven Armor Training.</b> You have proficiency with
        light and medium armor.</string>
    <string name="keenSenses"><b>Keen Senses.</b> You have proficiency in Perception</string>
    <string name="feyAncestry"><b>Fey Ancestry.</b> You have advantage on saving throws
        against being charmed, and magic can't put you to sleep.</string>
    <string name="elfTrance"><b>Trance.</b> Elves don't need to sleep. Instead, they
        meditate deeply, remaining semiconscious, for 4 hours a day. After resting this way,
        you gain the same benefit that a human does from 8 hours of sleep.</string>
    <string name="elfWeaponTraining"><b>Elf Weapon Training.</b> You have proficiency with
        the longsword, shortsword, shortbow, and longbow.</string>
    <string name="elfCantrip"><b>Cantrip.</b> You know one cantrip of your choice from the wizard
        spell list. Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for it.</string>
    <string name="maskOfTheWild"><b>Mask of the Wild.</b> You can attempt to hide even when you are
        only lightly obscured by foliage, heavy rain, falling snow, mist, or other natural
        phenomena.</string>
    <string name="sunlightSensitivity"><b>Sunlight Sensitivity.</b> You have disadvantage on
        attack rolls and on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on sight when you, the target of
        your attack, or whatever you are trying to perceive is in direct sunlight.</string>
    <string name="drowMagic"><b>Drow Magic.</b> You know the <i>dancing lights</i> cantrip. When
        you reach 3rd level, you can cast the <i>faerie fire</i> spell once per day. When you reach
        5th level, you can also cast the <i>darkness</i> spell once per day. Charisma is your
        spellcasting ability for these spells.</string>
    <string name="drowWeaponTraining"><b>Drow Weapon Training.</b> You have proficiency with
        rapiers, shortswords, and hand crossbows.</string>
    <string name="brave"><b>Brave.</b> You have advantage on saving  throws against being
        frightened.</string>
    <string name="lucky"><b>Lucky.</b> When you roll a 1 on an attack roll, ability check, or
        saving throw, you can reroll the die and must use the new roll.</string>
    <string name="halflingNimbleness"><b>Halfling Nimbleness.</b> You can move through the space of
        any creature that is of a size larger than yours.</string>
    <string name="naturallyStealthy"><b>Naturally Stealthy.</b> You can attempt to hide even when
        you are obscured only by a creature that is at least one size larger than you.</string>
    <string name="stoutResilience"><b>Stout Resilience.</b> You have advantage on saving throws
        against poison, and you have resistance against poison damage.</string>
    <string name="gnomeCunning"><b>Gnome Cunning.</b> You have advantage on all Intelligence,
        Wisdom, and Charisma saving throws against magic.</string>
    <string name="draconicAncestry"><b>Draconic Ancestry.</b> You have draconic ancestry. Choose
        one type of dragon from the Draconic Ancestry tab. Your breath weapon and damage resistance
        are determined by the dragon type.</string>
    <string name="breathWeapon"><b>Breath Weapon.</b> You can use your action to exhale destructive
        energy. Your draconic ancestry determines the size, shape, and damage type of the
        exhalation.\n\tWhen you use your breath weapon, each creature in the area of exhalation
        must make a saving throw, the type of which is determined by your draconic ancestry. The DC
        for this saving throw equals 8 + your Constitution modifier + your proficiency bonus. A
        creature takes 2d6 damage on a failed save, and half as much damage on a successful one.
        The damage increases to 3d6 at 6th level, 4d6 at 11th level, and 5d6 at 16th level.
        /n/tAfter you use your breath weapon, you can't use it again until after you complete
        a long rest.</string>
    <string name="draconicResistance"><b>Damage Resistance.</b> You have resistance to the damage
        type associated with your draconic ancestry.</string>
    <string name="naturalIllusionist"><b>Natural Illusionist.</b> You know the
        <i>minor illusion</i> cantrip. Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for it.</string>
    <string name="speakWithSBeasts"><b>Speak with Small Beasts.</b> Through sounds and gestures,
        you can communicate simple ideas with Small or smaller beasts.</string>
    <string name="arificersLore"><b>Artificer's Lore.</b> Whenever you make an Intelligence
        (History) check related to magic items, alchemical objects, or technological devices, you
        can add twice your proficiency bonus, instead of your normal proficiency bonus.</string>
    <string name="tinker"><b>Tinker.</b> You have proficiency with artisan’s tools (tinker’s tools).
        Using those tools, you can spend 1 hour and 10 gp worth of materials to construct a Tiny
        clockwork device (AC 5, 1 hp). The device ceases to function after 24 hours (unless you
        spend 1 hour repairing it to keep the device functioning), or when you use your action to
        dismantle it; at that time, you can reclaim the materials used to create it. You can have
        up to three such devices active at a time.\n\tWhen you create a device, choose one of the
        following options:\n<i>Clockwork Toy.</i> This toy is a clockwork animal, monster, or
        person, such as a frog, mouse, bird, dragon, or soldier. When placed on the ground, the toy
        moves 5 feet across the ground on each of your turns in a random direction. It makes noises
        as appropriate to the creature it represents.\n<i>Fire Starter.</i> The device produces a
        miniature flame, which you can use to light a candle, torch, or campfire. Using the device
        requires your action.\n<i>Music Box.</i> When opened, this music box plays a single song at
        a moderate volume. The box stops playing when it reaches the song’s end or when it is
        closed.</string>
    <string name="helfVersatility"><b>Skill Versatility.</b> You gain proficiency in two skills of
        your choice.</string>
    <string name="menacing"><b>Menacing.</b> You gain proficiency in the Intimidation
        skill.</string>
    <string name="relentlessEndurance"><b>Relentless Endurance.</b> When you are reduced to 0 hit
        points but not killed outright, you can drop to 1 hit point instead. You can't use this
        feature again until you finish a long rest.</string>
    <string name="savageAttacks"><b>Savage Attacks.</b> When you score a critical hit with a melee
        weapon attack, you can roll one of the weapon's damage dice one additional time and add it
        to the extra damage of the critical hit.</string>
    <string name="hellishResistance"><b>Hellish Resistance.</b> You have resistance to
        fire damage.</string>
    <string name="infernalLegacy"><b>Infernal Legacy.</b> You know the <i>thaumaturgy</i> cantrip.
        Once you reach the 3rd level, you can cast the <i>hellish rebuke</i> spell once per day
        as a 2nd-level spell. Once you reach 5th level, you can also cast the <i>darkness</i> spell
        once per day. Charisma is your spellcasting ability for these spells.</string>

    <!--We will probably use string formatting for traits strings.
    \n for new lines (between traits)
    %1$s for a string. The string requires code found in the fragment-->


</resources>
